How can we impact that exact location?
Sir, there's some confusion.
We've got today's coordinates back
for tomorrow's op, including Point 4065.
Army told us to hold because they wanted
to commence the ground assault--
They did.
But as soon as they climbed the hill,
they were ambushed.
Unfortunately, not just 4065,
that's the story of
every single peak we've bombed.
How is it possible, sir?
Seventy percent of our bombs
have been on target.
Bombs are striking the peaks,
but with
a 100-to-150-metre margin of error,
they're not directly destroying
the enemy sangars.
And we've also learned
from the enemy's RT intercepts
that the shrapnel from our bomb blasts
are unable to penetrate the sangar rocks.
So their strategy
has become very simple now.
The moment they hear our jets approaching,
they take cover inside their sangars.
And when our Army climbs,
they come right back out.
That means
our sophisticated high-altitude strategy
is being neutralized by prehistoric rocks.
In the Kargil sector, the Pakistan Army
has committed gross atrocities
against our fallen soldiers.
According to defense sources,
the bodies do not just bear bullet wounds,
the savagery includes
burning of flesh with cigarettes,
rupturing eardrums with hot rods,
gouging out eyes, and mutilating limbs.
Amid growing public outrage,
the Indian Army has promised
a befitting reply to the Pakistan Army's
inhuman message within 48 hours.
Within 48 hours?
Even 48 years wouldn't be enough.
I'm sorry.
We tried.
Jai Hind, sir.
One of the captive Pakistani soldiers
has regained consciousness, sir.
Tony, I'll see you.
Let us through.
We won't spare them.
Boys!
Let us go, sir!
They deserve the same treatment
that they gave to our brothers.
This is the Indian Army!
We're all seething with rage.
But whatever we'll do,
will be on the battlefield.
Not with a half-dead enemy like this.
You have two options. Either you confess,
or my men outside are waiting for you.
They all know you're from 12 NLI.
If I give them a free hand--
Go ahead, sir.
I have killed their brothers.
Aren't you afraid of dying?
How many times
will you kill a dead person?
So what did a dead person get
by doing all this?
The same thing
that you get.
A salary.
Now you won't even get that.
The Commander of the 12 NLI,
the DGMO, General Musharraf,
they've all publicly stated
that you're not part
of the Pakistani Army.
Which country's army
were you fighting for?
One that is refusing to even acknowledge
your existence?
You'll rot in a prison here.
Your family won't even get to know
where you vanished,
or how you passed away.
Sir,
I want to make a statement.
So after this confession, do you think
we'll get permission to cross the LoC?
Yes, we've seized all their Army IDs.
And military documents. In fact,
we've even seized the Stinger missiles
they used to attack you.
But if a country's army
is blatantly disowning its own soldiers,
what's the use of that evidence?
I'm surprised.
-I don't think that I've ever--
-Sartaj.
Can I take a look at those SAMs?
There's no radar cueing in this.
Sir.
Sartaj.
The Army might not
have to cross the LoC now.
Because we won't have to fly
above the clouds.
Now we can hit them from below.
Won't that put you
in the range of their SAMs?
Isn't that too risky, Tony?
They're heat-seeking missiles.
They have no radar cueing.
They have to lock the target visually.
When we won't be visible at night,
how will they lock on to us?
Sartaj, I need a secure line.
Chou, you're flying tonight, right?
-Yes, sir.
-One change.
I will fly with you.
We have to do a small experiment.
Releasing in three, two, one…
Now! Bombs away.
Bombs away.
Job done, Arrows. Return to base now.
Copy that.
Arrow 1, confirm losing altitude.
-Check intention.
-Negative, sir.
We're still above the clouds.
Maybe some glitch in the radar, sir.
Get into the sangars! Quick!
Move! Move! Move!
-Sir, communication's secure on channel 2.
-Copy that.
-Let's enter the target valley.
-Roger that.
1500 meters above the target.
The peak is visible, but not the sangar.
-Let's go further down, Chou.
-Roger, sir.
Doesn't that sound
a little closer than usual today?
Chou, do you see anything?
Negative. Let's go further down.
Okay, Chou. But let's be careful.
-We're in their missile range now.
-Roger that.
Okay, that's it, Chou.
Target acquired, 1,000 meters.
Let's get the hell out of here.
Roger that, sir.
Sir, I've checked the model
of their missiles.
They don't have radar homing.
They are heat-seeking missiles.
Which means we can use that
to our advantage.
By flying below the clouds at night,
we can hit their sangars directly.
Sorry, come again, Tony.
You want to do visually guided bombing
at night in these mountains?
We're in moon phase, sir.
The white peaks shine at night.
Visibility isn't a problem.
But, Tony,
by the time you finish the trials,
the moon cycle would have ended.
We'll have to wait another 15 days,
and we don't have that much time.
I'm sorry.
But in tonight's bombing run,
we've already conducted the trial.
We can start right away.
That was reckless, Tony.
But they will never expect this.
So, let's do it.
Low-altitude night bombing
is officially on.
We're in the sector now. Let's go down.
Roger.
Descending now.
They're coming in close again.
Captain. Get the SAM.
Something is fishy.
We know nothing about their plan.
We should hide in the sangars.
If they're daring to enter
our missile range again,
then like last time,
we will bring them down again.
Get the other SAM too.
And, everyone else,
hide in the sangars! Quickly!
Two thousand meters above the target.
-Let's go down to 1,000.
-Roger.
Hurry up!
-Stay sharp, they can come from anywhere.
-Sir, where do we aim?
Arrow 2, I have a visual of the peak.
Visual confirmed, Arrow 1.
-Sir, they're coming from this direction.
-Take aim.
Arrow 2, stand by to acquire target.
On stand by.
-Can you see the jets?
-No, sir.
It's too dark.
They're coming straight at us, sir.
Try to get a lock.
Yes, sir, trying to lock on.
But I'm not able to.
Arrow 2, after release,
you've six seconds to climb up.
Copy that.
If we fire without
locking onto the target, we'll miss it.
But we've got no other option.
-Arrow 2, bombs on standby.
-Roger.
Fire!
Bombs away.
Bombs away!
Pull up. Exercise caution. Reheat.
I testify there is no god but Allah…
Flying Officer Dhali, you've became
the youngest pilot in the Indian Air Force
to carry out a low-altitude
night bombing mission.
Thank you for trusting me, sir.
This was a real honor.
Boys, you've done it.
Your bombs have annihilated
the enemy positions at Point 4065.
The Army will reclaim that peak
within 24 hours.
This will change
the face of the Kargil war.
It was just one peak tonight.
There are still
ten moonlit nights left, sir.
Bombs away!
Sir, we've lost Bashir post too.
That means we can no longer send supplies
to any of our positions
in the Yaldor Sector.
The Kargil War has been underway
for nearly two months now.
And with the Indian Air Force's
low-altitude night bombing campaign,
the tide of the war appears
to be turning in India's favor.
Amid continuous bombardment
by the Indian Air Force,
the mountains of Kargil now echo
with the thunder of Bofors guns.
Armed with Bofors artillery,
the Indian Army
is shelling enemy positions
around the clock.
The defenses of the enemy
have crumbled owing to relentless pressure
maintained by our ground forces.
and the heavy attrition
caused on the enemy
by the effective air strikes
and the pounding
undertaken by our artillery.
While Pakistan continues to suffer
heavy losses on the battlefield,
its diplomatic position
is deteriorating as well.
Pakistan's claim that the fighters
in Kargil are Mujahideen
has completely fallen apart.
Statements from captured soldiers
have made it clear
that these are not Mujahideen,
but regular soldiers
of the Pakistani Army.
I'm a soldier
of the 12th Northern Light Infantry.
In the beginning, we had plenty of food
and ammunition,
but when the Indian Army
launched its attack,
our superiors abandoned us.
If the Indian Army hadn't captured us,
we would've starved to death, sir.
General Zia.
Remove his name from all military records.
And tell Hassan
that any troops sent forward
must have their military IDs confiscated.
Are we even winning this war?
Sir, when have they ever told us the truth
about this operation?
If you want to see the truth of this war,
you'll have to come with me, Mian sahib.
Following two weeks
of relentless joint operations
by the Army and Air Force,
India has recaptured
almost all the Pakistan army
occupied peaks in Kargil.
However, some crucial peaks
in Drass and Batalik,
such as Tiger Hill and Point 4875,
still remain under Pakistani control.
Welcome to Skardu, sir.
Mian sahib has come to see the reality of
this war with his own eyes, Gen. Hassan.
It would be better not to hide anything.
Right, sir.
Let's head to the officers' mess.
I'll give you the complete update.
General Hassan, the truth of democracy
is revealed at the polling booth
and the reality of war in the hospital.
Sir, this tent was empty till yesterday.
But today, the Indian Air Force
launched a major attack,
inflicting heavy casualties on our troops.
Otherwise, everything
is under control, sir.
Pakistan is winning the war.
Is this how we're winning the war?
Shame on an army like this,
that cannot stand by its own soldiers.
Who allowed Mian sahib into the base?
When he isn't giving any support
from Islamabad, then he has no right--
Sir, we have lost Aqeel post.
-Indian Air Force is now attacking at--
-Aziz has briefed me on everything.
Don't miss the big picture, Hassan.
Sir, the big picture is this,
that we had no idea
that such a small operation
would spiral into such a large-scale war.
Every assessment we made
about the Indian Army
and the Indian Air Force has proven wrong.
And now the Indian Army and Air Force
are ready to fight to the death.
I want solutions, not complaints.
There's only one solution, sir.
I think we should withdraw from this war.
Hassan, it was your idea
to capture all those Indian posts, right?
And I take full responsibility
for the loss of this war, sir.
I am sorry, sir.
Now, I'll not send
any of my soldiers forward.
My conscience
doesn't allow me to do this, sir.
General Hassan,
I hereby relieve you and your conscience
from this operation.
Hand over all your responsibilities
to General Mahmud.
That will be all.
Sir.
Pervez, is everything okay?
Everything is fine.
Pervez, Pakistan Air Force
will not cross the LoC.
So this means
the Pakistan Air Force
will do nothing
in this country's biggest operation.
Did you consult the Air Force and Navy
before starting all of this?
Forget consultation.
You didn't even think
it necessary to inform us.
And now, when your plan is failing,
you suddenly remember
the Pakistan Air Force.
Then we have to hand it
to the Indian Air Force, Mehdi sahib.
Mehdi sahib,
the Indian Air Force
must have also
joined this operation overnight, right?
As Air Chief, my answer is clear.
In such terrain, I will not send my pilots
on suicide missions.
But, Pervez, as your friend,
I can do something
that will prevent the Indian Air Force
from targeting your sangars.
Arrow 2, preparing to descend.
Roger.
-Arrow 2, approaching target.
-On your tail, sir.
There. Aim over there.
-Approaching target. Stay on my tail.
-Roger.
They're here.
Arrow 2, bombs on standby.
Missile! Pull up! Pull up! Pull up!
The missile's effective range
is 10,000 feet.
If we climb, it'll fall behind.
Copy that.
-Pull up! Keep pulling up!
-Pulling up!
Hard right!
What the hell?
How are they able to aim in the dark?
I don't know, sir.
Thankfully, you spotted it in time.
We were lucky. The darkness of night
helped me spot it quickly.
Let's get the hell out of here, Arrow 2.
Sir.
Jai Hind, sir.
At ease.
Military Intelligence
has intercepted an RT conversation
between Skardu Base and Point 4875.
Please.
Base to 4875, fighters approaching.
Two fighter jets are approaching.
-Get the SAM.
-Okay, sir.
Tell me their position and directions.
060 radial, cruising 1,650 kph.
Expect visual contact in 30 seconds.
The Pakistan Air Force
is installing radars near the peaks.
Now, if our jets fly low over Drass,
the enemy will know their exact heading.
This changes everything.
Our surprise element has been compromised.
We wanted to reclaim Point 5280
in the last sorties of the moon cycle.
Because this peak in Kaksar
was their link to Drass and Batalik.
Not only was this choking NH1
for the Indian Army,
but it's also clear
from Military Intelligence now
that this is the route
for Pakistan Army's fresh reinforcements
to all Drass and Batalik peaks,
including Tiger Hill.
We're down to two choices.
Either the Mirage 2000 strikes
from outside the missile range,
or the Army climbs inch by inch
and fights a long war.
This will really hurt us.
But there are no
unconventional strategies left to try.
It's time for the Golden Arrows
to stand down.
Tony.
Yes, sir.
Sir.
We can hit 5280.
What did you not understand, Baldy?
They have radars now.
Patney sir just explained that.
Exactly, sir. We can trick those radars.
Arrows, we've done this before.
Ahuja sir's Transport Jet strategy.
Yes.
We can do it, sir.
Sir, and we should do it today.
There's only one moonlit night left, sir.
Ahuja sir trained us
for this very day, sir.
Trained you.
Where? When?
In the flatlands?
In daytime? In peacetime?
The Transport Jet formation
is a very difficult formation in itself.
Right now, we have to fly
in the world's most dangerous mountains,
and that too at night.
In the middle of a war. Get real, boys.
Sir…
Whatever we've done in this war so far,
day bombing, night bombing,
high altitude, low altitude,
we hadn't practiced for that either.
That was different, Dhali.
In this type of terrain,
such a difficult formation requires
a completely different type of readiness.
And we are, sir.
We are fully ready.
Baldy, you haven't flown
a single sortie here.
I'm sorry, sir, but that's not my fault.
I've memorized every map ten times over.
But you didn't give me
even a single sortie.
Which is fine. That's your call.
But readiness
is not about the number of sorties.
Madhavi is pregnant, Baldy.
Sir. I don't see the connection, sir.
That's my personal matter.
This can't be the reason
to stop me from flying.
Baldy is right.
This is the life
we all signed up for, sir.
Let this be my call, sir.
Baldy should fly.
Sir, training or no training,
one thing we've definitely learned
is how to back each other up.
Sir, you told me once.
No one's ever ready for war.
If we'll go down, we'll go together, sir.
Chou, prepare the jets.
The boys are ready.
Arrows,
it'll be my honor to lead you.
Boys, we can fool them
with a Transport Jet formation,
but for two to three minutes at most.
So right after takeoff,
we'll split into four pairs
and approach through different valleys.
We'll fly low, below the ridgelines,
staying deep in the valleys
so their radars can't detect us.
We must stay perfectly in sync
through the valleys,
so we all reach Delta Point,
where the four valleys converge,
at the same time.
There, we'll form
eight jet transport formation.
On their radars,
instead of eight separate jets,
they'll see a single large
transport aircraft.
Is that clear, boys?
Okay.
Met hotline, sir.
Heavy cloud formation ahead
on Arrow 3's flight path.
Alert them.
Arrow 3, scanners.
Heavy cloud buildup
on radial 030, 80 kilometers.
Exercise strong caution.
Arrow 3, consider alternate route.
Arrow 1, copy. Stand by for update.
There is no alternate route.
We have two options.
Either abort the mission,
or go through the clouds.
In that case, Arrow 3, abort approach.
In these mountains,
you are not to fly through the clouds.
Arrow 1, if we abort,
everyone will have to abort.
-That's okay. Arrows, stand by to abort.
-Arrow 3, monitored.
-Arrow 5, monitored.
-…monitored.
Arrow 4, stand by to pull up.
Arrows, wait!
We can make it through the clouds.
Dhali, you've done this before.
Haven't done it in the mountains, Baldy!
If the peak in front of us is over 4,000,
we'll crash into the rocks.
Arrow 4, what's your suggestion?
That peak is 4,320 meters high.
If we maintain 800,
it will take us exactly ten seconds
to reach 4,500 meters.
Arrow 4, are you sure
about your calculations?
Sir, they don't call me Professor
for nothing.
Okay, Arrow 4. Go ahead.
But I want all my pilots at Delta Point.
Yes, sir. You will.
Arrow 3, follow my lead. Maintain 800.
Professor sahib, we're in your hands now.
Speed steady at 800.
Altitude 3,250. Climbing!
All right, maintaining thrust.
Dhali, max reheat!
3,750.
4,000.
Visibility is zero, but we're on track.
Five seconds left.
4,250.
-Pull up!
-Pulling up!
4,500!
Arrow 3 and 4 at Delta. Joining up.
Well done, boys!
Arrows, join up in close formation.
Time to become a dot, boys.
Okay, boys, this mission
isn't there in any manual.
If we pull this off, we'll write
the manual ourselves.
Let's do this, boys.
Transport aircraft flying in
from south westerly heading.
-Details please.
-Currently at 27,000 feet.
What's a transport aircraft
doing here at this hour?
Check the movement sheet.
Tell me which plane it is.
Hamza, check the movement sheet. Hurry.
-You, get the SAMs out.
-Okay, sir.
Arrows, 30 seconds to descent.
Nothing on the movement sheet.
No idea what aircraft it is.
Descend now.
Blip is rapidly losing altitude
in your direction.
Dhali, Baldy, it's show time.
-Copy, sir.
-Roger.
Arrows, split.
It's a decoy! It's a decoy!
It's not one, but eight jets
coming from different directions!
What are you doing? Why aren't you firing?
Sir, I can't see them.
There's just sound
coming from all directions.
I don't know where to aim.
There are eight jets! Shoot them down!
Arrow 2, missile at twelve o'clock.
Break right.
Missile evaded. Arrow 3 and 4,
clear to fire. Smoke them up, boys.
Those two jets are coming this way.
Give it to me.
In three, two, one, now!
Bombs away!
Arrows, Ahuja would be proud of us.
Let's get back home now.
For the past two months,
all of us have fought this war together.
The most unconventional war in history.
Today, the Golden Arrows
have completed a suicide mission
with zero casualties,
proving that Indian Air Force fighters,
they just don't touch the impossible,
they break right through it.
Yes!
-Yes!
Victory
is just a few peaks away.
And you, Arrows, have given us the time
to ready our most powerful weapon,
the Mirages.
Their laser-guided bombs are live,
locked, and loaded to conquer Tiger Hill.
Boys, for the past several days,
we've just been hearing stories
of system errors
and the struggles of our fellow soldiers.
But now,
our own laser-guided bombs are ready.
During this conflict, the frustration
and fury that has built up inside us
is no less than any bomb.
Battle Axes, are you ready
to deal the final blow
-to the enemy in this war?
-Yes, sir!
-Vanquish the enemy!
Nambiar, laser on. Ready?
I'm more than ready, sir.
Ten kilometers away. Start zooming in.
Visual acquired.
Enemy sangars clear as day.
Let's crush the ego
of little Pakistan once and for all.
Roger. Bombs away.
Bombs away.
After nearly 11 hours
of relentless combat,
supported by precision strikes
from Indian Air Force Mirage jets,
Indian forces have recaptured Tiger Hill.
This decisive victory
restores Indian control
over the strategic heights of Drass,
marking a significant turning point
in the Kargil conflict.
Along with Tiger Hill,
the Indian Air Force's Mirage jets
also attacked the Pakistani supply base
at Muntho Dhalo in the Batalik sector,
in which about
300 Pakistani soldiers were killed.
Where is Mian sahib?
Mian sahib has left
for Washington D.C., all by himself.
Thank you for agreeing to see me today.
You barged in here
and blackmailed me
with the threat of nuclear war.
I'm sorry. Nuclear war?
I don't follow, Mr. President.
Either you are a very good actor
or you have no idea
what's happening in your own backyard.
Your army has mobilized nuclear assets.
We are tracking them right now.
I don't know what you're talking about.
I promise, Mr. President.
I told you before, Nawaz,
I need to speak with whoever is in charge,
whoever runs your country.
I'm in charge.
I'm here with the mandate
of people of Pakistan.
And it's that mandate
you're looking to protect by coming here?
Yes. Of course.
Let me be very clear.
Unless you came here to announce
the unilateral withdrawal
of your troops from Indian territory,
we don't have much to talk about.
I can withdraw my troops.
But I have to show something
to my people, for this conflict.
And only you can help me,
Mr. President, with this.
Let me get this straight.
You want me to broker your retreat?
I thought you didn't want
any outside interference.
Mr. Vajpayee is not taking my calls.
And if I return empty-handed,
Mr. President,
the same people who started this fire
will throw me back
in the same fire and burn me.
Mr. Sharif, the United States
will not be dragged
into a civil-military tug of war
between Islamabad and Rawalpindi.
I have two statements here.
One commends you
for withdrawing troops right away
and committing to regional stability.
And the other condemns you
for illegally occupying Indian soil
and threatening world peace
with nuclear weapons.
Call your cabinet,
take your time…
and decide how you want
to be remembered, Mr. Sharif.
After hours of tense negotiations
in Washington D.C.,
Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif has announced
a unilateral withdrawal
of Pakistani troops
from the heights of Kargil.
The Kargil war is now effectively over,
and India has won.
My ISI sources say
Mian sahib is preparing
to pin the whole blame on you.
There's talk of a court-martial.
We lost this war, sir.
General Mahmud, you worry too much.
We've lost Kargil, not Pakistan.
Get the fear of a court-martial
out of your mind…
and start preparing to impose martial law.
There's a huge uproar in Pakistan.
The Pakistan Army claims
that they were winning the war
until Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif
buckled under US pressure.
This news is spreading rapidly,
and effigies of the Prime Minister
are being burnt in many cities.
The families of Pakistani soldiers
are demanding answers from the government.
Are their loved ones alive or not?
Sir.
The Pakistan Army
is refusing to accept the bodies.
Bury them according to their religion.
-But, sir--
-They were soldiers.
They might have forgotten this,
but not us.
There's a difference
between us and them.
-Right?
-Yes, sahib!
Climbing treacherous heights
and fighting a brutal war,
our army pushed them back,
proving once and for all…
the devastating cost
of crossing swords
with us.
When were you gonna tell me?
Post delivery?
The day you didn't have a sortie.
-Congratulations, Madhavi.
-Thank you, sir.
Could you hear the sound?
Loud and clear.
The Indian Air Force
has played a crucial role
in the victory of Kargil.
So, how are you all feeling?
Look, we're razor blades.
Our job is to cut
whenever and wherever we're told.
Thinking or feeling isn't part of the job.
Sir, what was it like to lose
Squadron Leader Ahuja
in the initial days
of the operation?
Sir, this is my question too.
Ahuja sir could've turned back
if he wanted to.
But was he right to act
beyond the call of duty?
Because of his decision,
we not only lost a jet,
but we also lost a highly valuable pilot.
Sir, I just want to know your opinion.
Sir, may I?
Sure.
Have any of you
ever been inside a MiG-21 cockpit?
No, sir.
I'll tell you what a MiG-21
means to a fighter pilot.
First, I will strap you into a seat
from which you cannot move.
Then I'll place a few hundred controls
and about 4,000 liters
of fuel all around you.
A tiny spark
can turn your jet into a bomb.
And you're expected to fly this live bomb
faster than the speed of sound.
Small mistake,
and you can turn into ash.
This is what a MiG-21 fighter pilot
faces every single day.
Now I want to ask you, sir.
If you were in that cockpit that day,
what would've been your first priority?
-To stay alive, sir.
-To stay alive.
Exactly, sir.
That day, in that situation,
Flight Commander
Squadron Leader Ajay Ahuja
chose to put someone else's survival
ahead of his own life.
No one has the right
to question whether he did right or wrong.
Any more questions?
-No, sir.
Jai Hind.
Tony?
He went to Delhi.
Paperwork.
Happy landings, boys.
Tony?
How are you?
I spoke to Kamal on the phone yesterday.
She didn't tell me.
Alka, you know…
I'm…
very sorry.
The thing is…
I couldn't muster the courage to face you.
That day,
I should've been there with Ajay.
Had I been there, maybe…
Coffee?
On the day of the cremation,
what I said…
Tony, I was just so angry.
But you were right.
I… broke your trust.
Tony…
forgive yourself.
Look, the truth is
that on that day, neither you,
nor I, nor Ankur,
nor anyone else could've stopped Ajay.
That's just the way he was.
Forgive yourself, Tony. Please.
Subtitle translation by: Shrey Ravi